do you love laughing do you believe that
laughter is the best medicine to solve
many problems well I think I do and
that's why we are bringing you something
which is all about laughter welcome to
the first ever episode of wellness 360
at home
brought to you by ICICI Lombard hi amber
Tonopah hi and today we're bringing you
something very special I laughed a riot
I strongly believe that one is at their
best when laughing and if you have to be
the best version of yourself you have to
start laughing from your heart and laugh
your heart out today I'm happy to be
welcoming somebody who's a master of
laughter and in the lockdown he is
giving us laughter at lockdown who is he
well joining us here at the Wellness 360
and who is somebody who is a master of
laughter across the world he is a
founder and coordinator of the laughter
yoga movement worldwide a medical doctor
from Mumbai but he's popularly known
across the world as a good world
giggling by London Times he started the
first laughter Club ever with his five
members in the year 1995 about 25 years
back and today in 2020 there are about
16,000 laughter yoga clubs across
hundred different countries a very proud
and very happy and laughter as a
movement please welcome well laughter
riot sure the wine list 360 at home
brought to you by icy echelon bad one
only dr. modern Kataria with us right
now
welcome dr. Baden Kataria is so good to
have you as a with us as the first guest
for the first ever episode and I'm sure
it's going to be a lotta diet so without
a delay let's all laugh and let's all
laugh together with the family members
next to each other such that we bring
this together and make sure we are
laughing our heart out
let the laughter begin hello my name is
madame Kataria I'm the founder of
laughter yoga clubs worldwide and if you
are wondering why I am laughing actually
I am laughing for no reason at all and
this is what I'm going to teach you
today for centuries people knew that
love is the best medicine it has many
scientifically proven benefits but until
now there was no reliable method of
getting benefits of laughter until we
found love to yoga people ask me a
question why should we force ourselves
to love why not whoo laughs naturally by
watching funny movies and comedies I
just want to share with you that natural
laughter which comes in a real life
hardly lasts for two to three seconds at
a time that's not good enough to give
you the benefits so this is where
laughter yoga comes in size tells us
that to get the benefits of laughter one
must love at least for 10 to 15 minutes
it should be a sustained laughter so
since we in love yoga we do love as a
form of exercise so we can laugh as much
as we want now when I leave this
exercises you please keep in mind that
you're not supposed to be watching this
broadcast actually I want you to laugh
along with me and do this exercises so
that you know how it feels so please put
your mobile phones or your iPads and
just the laptops put on the table and
just get ready and invite all your
family members to laugh with me and you
will feel much better so I'm going to
teach you a lot of new laughter yoga
exercises
another thing you must keep in mind is
that love is like a breathing exercise
yoga part of love frees combining
breathing and laughing together which
brings more oxygen to your body and
brain so are you ready to laugh with me
ok let's get started
just keep one thing in mind laughter
yoga is an exercise program you're
laughing on purpose does not matter just
try to laugh with me so this is one
second you even if you feel a little bit
awkward in the beginning just try to do
some laughter exercises with me so I'm
going to lead you some laughter
exercises which are very popular and we
go step by step so step number one is
clapping so put your hands together like
this normally we clap like this but in
yoga like this exercise and it goes like
ha ha ha so this is activating our
laughter muscles so are you ready for
the next step why we call laughter yoga
what is yoga and laughter combining
breathing exercises from yoga deep
breathing exercises
and laughter exercises that brings more
oxygen to our body and brain and that
makes us feel more healthy and more
energetic now if you see in yoga people
tell to exhale longer than you inhale so
same thing what we do in laughter yoga
so what do we what do we do when we
laugh we are exhaling so guess what
in even doing laughters and exercise you
are exhaling lot of carbon dioxide out
of your lungs and that is replaced by
fresh air which has more oxygen and it's
very healthy for your body okay so
please do one breathing exercise with me
put your hands out like this and take
long deep breath and bring your heads
together to your just take a long deep
breath
[Music]
so this is the technique very simple you
fill up your lungs with a lot of air you
hold your breath it builds up a positive
pressure and me when you laugh it out
you laugh a bit longer so this is why
this is laughter yoga exercise okay put
your hands together no I guess you are
doing I am NOT asking to watch please do
it with me
put your hands out take a long deep
breath I know you can't laugh like me
I'm a laughter master but whatever way
doesn't matter even if he's like okay do
it again with me take long deep breath
in so it's like a practice like any art
you have learn the art of laughing and
what is behind art of laughing is a
science of breathing let me tell you why
people fall sick because we don't
breathe correctly with stress tension of
a breath is very shallow very small we
don't take long deep breaths so that's
why laughter yoga allows you to exercise
your lungs and fill up your lungs with a
lot of oxygen and this is still a
laughter exercise but these laughter
exercises can be turned into natural
laughter with practice we can do it I'll
show you some techniques so friends
another exercise which I want to teach
you before we do start doing laughter
exercises this is very good exercise
called childlike tears childlike
playfulness as you know that children
can laugh 300 to 400 times in a day and
we love very little only ten times 15
times hi children can laugh so much and
we love so little because children don't
use too few more comedies no nothing no
brain is not anymore children laugh when
they play physically play so whole
concept of laughter Yoga is like you
become like a child for some time and
then you see laughter will start flowing
like a fountain out of it so let's do
one exercise with me
it's called childlike play where
good very good yay good with me please
very good very good yay normally we put
our hands out like hey can you do that
very good very good yeah so this is the
exercise now we come to the regular
laughter exercises so friends first
laughter exercise I invented in 1995 was
namaste laughter so in India when we
greet each other we join our hand I must
say so what I suggest please join your
hand if you have your family members
around you just look at them and say
[Laughter]
please please look at each other and
just look at me and very good yay very
good very good
yay so this is first exercise second
exercise is called milkshake lock so
since I am from Punjab this is also
called lasse laughter so hold two
imaginary glasses of milk going to mix
it rice pour into each other do it with
me
Oh two glasses and if you are lactose
intolerant if you don't like milk you
can mix it and throw it okay let's do it
[Laughter]
let's take a long deep breath in between
laughter exercise you must breathe okay
put your hands out take a long deep
breath in one more time take long deep
breath so this is this exercise is one
of the best exercise for reducing stress
you know there are so many methods for
stress reduction but this is
cost-effective very simple anybody can
do it and there are three kinds of
stress we have in in our life physical
stress mental stress emotional stress so
all these three types of stress just one
exercise that Slavkin yoga second I just
want to make you aware that now we are
facing a threat of pandemic coronavirus
spreading all over the world
who are the people who will survive
against the virus the one who has to
have a strong immune system now over the
25 years we have several scientific
research studies which shows that if you
laugh every day it will make your immune
system stronger and you will not fall
second most important thing about
coronavirus is that if your lungs are
strong if your lungs have more oxygen
Wiress will not attack your lungs so
this is kind of a breathing exercise you
increase your breathing capacity so that
we can save ourself from this virus
attack I guarantee you will not fall
sick you will not get virus if you laugh
every single day so for while you need
to laugh every day so I'll tell you how
you can laugh I'll teach you some
exercises that third important benefit
of love to you guys keep your mind
positive now with all the negative
circumstances we are facing challenges
we are facing the mind always go into
negative more we have fear we have
anxiety but we what's going to happen so
therefore by doing this laughter
exercises your brain will pump out lot
of happy chemicals called endorphins
serotonin and dopamine oxytocin all
these four important hormones will be
secreted just by doing this laughter
exercises and these hormones will keep
your mind positive even if there is lot
of negativity you will not get anxiety
about it okay now this is my favorite
exercise please do it with me this is
called credit card bill laughter so
imagine put your hand like this this is
your bill for your Visa card MasterCard
or maybe American Express whatever card
you have okay so look at your bill and
maybe you show it to your family friends
around and laugh about it it's not funny
you get a bill for your visa guys we can
laugh about anything
please show your family member say with
me
very good very good yay very good good
yay
ok the next exercise I'm going to teach
you is argument laughter now even if you
want to fight with someone fight
laughing okay so this is how please do
it with me
drag your finger this is an argument
done to your family member as they say
with me please very good very good yeah
okay let me tell you friends this
laughter yoga exercise is a very good
exercise for your mind it cleans your
mind from the negative thoughts and it
brings more positive thoughts so this is
that's why I call it mental floss
laughter it's not dental floss you clean
your teeth you have to clean your mind
you take a longer thread okay to like
this longer thread and wind it round
your finger and clean your mind and
laughs please do it with me come on
[Laughter]
and if your brain is not yet clean what
we can do is we take the brain out of
your head and put it on your hand and
wash it it's called brain wash okay put
your hand like this and put your brain
on it and wash it very good very good
very good
yay I hope you are enjoying these
exercises with me if you are doing it
with me very good and if you are not
doing it's very bad you should do it
[Laughter]
sometimes people ask me a question that
why not natural laughter why should we
force our self to laugh why not watch
funny movies comedies I want to tell you
that even if you watch best of the
comedies the next row laughter hardly
lasts for two to three seconds at a time
it's not very long and that's not good
enough to give you the benefits if you
want to get health benefits of laughter
all scientifically proven benefits you
must do laughter yoga exercises because
here love fresh longer and since this is
an exercise we can love as long as we
want and also laughing coming laughter
is beneficial Rudy if you love from the
belly from your diaphragm now I have a
very special of exercise for you it's
called lion laughter this is from yoga
so put your hands out take a long deep
breath in
and my laughing stick your tongue out
there laughs it's funny but it's very
good do it with me please take long deep
breath in this is a very good exercise
for your thyroid gland this is very good
exercise for your throat muscles as I
told you to increase your immunity of
your throat and upper respiratory tract
this is a fantastic loft do it with me
again take long deep breaths it's funny
but it's very very beneficial no reason
laughter comes from your diaphragm from
your belly and it exercises it massages
your all your internal organs this is
like a magic fingers which goes inside
your belly now you can do outside
massage through your muscles through
your body but what about your kidney
liver spleen get a pancreas with all the
internal organs they get massaged with
love that's why it's called magic
fingers so friends next next Locker
exercise is called Wi-Fi laughter now
these days people can survive without
food water everything but they cannot
survive without Wi-Fi so this is your
Wi-Fi router put your fingers like this
and when when you get a signal you start
laughing good good once again very good
very good
yay one exercise which is very favourite
when I wake up in the morning I start
laughing and I don't want to disturb
people so I've got a very special after
for you it's called silent laughter you
can laugh without sound
your mouths wide open and it's very good
you don't disturb anybody still you get
very good exercise for your abs okay
very come come
very good very good now I will do some
lovely exercises which are related to
Covent coronavirus we all know that we
must wash our hands so this is called
hand washes doctor please open the tab
and wash your hair next is social
distancing so let's do social distancing
laughter okay one thing is very
important you must not shake hand with
anybody
only the mistake so if you shake hand
you'll get a shot it's called electric
shock like this so like that we have
created sanitizing laughter you can and
while wearing a mask laughter look with
me mask laughter very good very good
now last few exercises I want to teach
you which you can do with your family
members now this is called dining table
laughter exercise dinner table laughter
exercises so this evening before you eat
your dinner please ask your family
members to laugh with love for one
minute challenge this is called
one minute challenge laughter it's very
difficult to love for one minute but you
can try even if it is 30 seconds is fine
okay so one way to challenge with your
family today on the inner table ready
one minute laughter okay go while
laughing keep looking at isn't it
infectious last message I want to tell
you is that to get the benefits of
laughter you must laugh every day and
there's a lot of love for yoga YouTube
videos available if you want to watch
them and this exercises is love to you
guys our channel and just love your
ongoing Google search we are number one
and you can learn all these exercises
are free you don't have to pay anything
and if I get to have more chance I will
request icy ice a long but officials to
get me on and make you love more and
more I've got hundreds of more exercises
the time is short but I just want to
tell you that this laughter exercises
can change your life I'm laughing for
the last 25 years I didn't I didn't
catch a cold even once so this is this
is how it makes your immune system
stronger to keep your mind positive is
very big challenge in this comedy in
this coronavirus and also forget about
corona you have a lot of other benefits
like benefit for your heart benefits for
your kidneys your liver your digestion
improves and also depression is number
one sickness in the word anxiety mental
illness is so many big you know why
America Germany and Japan are the
largest followers of laughter yoga and
there are more than 25 to 30 these such
studies or love yoga
and this is no laughing matter so please
keep laughing and even if you whatever I
shown you today you can practice some of
them and if you have any questions
please put in the chat box after a while
we'll start taking question and answers
with you and I love you I love I love to
laugh with you again and again and thank
you very much I say I say lumbar I am
your client I am very happy with your
service both my health insurance and my
travel insurance is with you so I I
really find it very useful and thank you
being so amazing and yes very good I
promise you I loved it I left everything
and I bet everyone was watching us back
home loving it with their families
family members and loved ones because if
you need to be happy you have to
understand the art and crafts and doctor
here this gave us a little more about
how you can be happy without doing
anything but just means of laughing so
doctor we also have the Q&A open now so
we can take some questions so are you
ready to the questions the doctor yeah
any questions please ask me very simple
yes of you with saying very good yeah
last exercise I want to do with the
viewers you please put your hand up and
bend at the end and take it behind and
well done other side laughs it's so many
things
doctor will we have questions coming in
let me ask the first question to you
first what are the true benefits of
laughing each day
only ten minutes see 10 to 15 minutes of
laughter yoga exercises as I told you it
will bring down the stress level a
stress is number one killer 70 to 80%
diseases are because of stress and
second I told you that it strengthens
your immune system immunoglobulin a is
the one for responsible for the
respiratory immunity and we have shown
in the scientific research that that
immunoglobulin D level goes up that's
why you are not less likely to catch
catch the virus third it keeps your mind
positive because there's so much of news
negative news your mind is going to go
negative so how can we how laughter yoga
can help you keep your mind positive is
by secreting those happy chemicals you
change your chemistry and you chemistry
is positive you will not get much
negative thoughts and love is also like
in aerobic exercise I told you that it's
it increases your heart rate improve
your blood supply and after laughing you
can sleep better it improves the quality
of the sleep and also it Social
Connector after laughing you exercise
all your facial muscles and after
laughing for few days you will see that
you'll start smiling automatically
that's a very good answer doctor we have
one more question from Cheryl Sharma
who's asking
how many times a day one should practice
this exercise I think at this stretch I
would say 10 to 15 minutes is of a
regular session okay but even without
you you got to learn this technique true
but if even if you have not learned just
from this session I would say that
please love one minute with your family
before having dinner or lunch and you
can do some of this exercise credit card
bill laughter milkshake laughter so even
if you do few minutes here and there
several times in a day with your
colleagues with your friends and you can
do this exercises with your
children children will love it so please
introduce love to yoga with your
children and these start with very good
question now that you already given the
answer that you can do this any part of
the day it's morning or evening or it's
afternoon before lunch before dinner
and we do this but I have one question
here who's saying up my sleeping clock
has been changed now I wake up in the
night sleep in the day what should I do
to normalize things a question by Nafees
amok he answer to that doctor
I think first is that even if you're not
getting sleep just lie down on the bed
stop all the lights just as it practice
and in the morning set up an alarm and
wake up even if you are not slept in the
night just wake up don't sleep in the
bay because to break the cycle you have
to be away during the day so please
don't try to sleep even if you haven't
got the sleep at night don't sleep in
the day for a few days once your body
get tired then you automatically start
getting the sleep cycle right unless you
are unnecessarily looking at the social
media online that is the common cause
people don't get much sleep doctor you
know what among all the questions
everybody's been telling you
complimenting you saying that you are
the laughter guru and be loving the
whole session excellent and amazing
laughter guru see from so far and many
more people but one more question is
coming here what is a correct time
fulfilled after yoga I think that has
already been answered but what are the
benefits for a better life from God of
Kumar Pandey okay see the best time to
laugh is in the morning because if you
laugh in the morning that carries it
sends you a good mood every so if you
mood is good in the first thing in the
morning and it carries through all body
and I want to tell you at 8:30 in the
morning on my Facebook page I do free
like Facebook live sessions you can
laugh with me every day at 8:30 laughter
guru is the page and please come and
laugh with me
is free of cost and please like my page
and you can come and love it
wow that's an amazing answer and how
many times a day should one do this
again just to number it I would say
there's no set like if you love for
10-15 minutes at the stretch in the
morning is fine or keep laughing
whenever you get an opportunity just for
fun I think best to you you your family
is the best before I would say make it
routine of dinner table laughter
exercise don't allow anybody to eat food
before you do some exercises otherwise
you can laugh while working also like
for example taking shower in the morning
having you get stuck in the traffic
whenever lockdown is remove so you went
driving also you could laugh in your
path and lady killable well with some
household chores cleaning cutting
vegetables fun Wow amazing
I have one more question I wanna ask you
a doctor how does it improve a personal
Spurrier if you keep practicing the
laughter therapy throughout every day
laughter you guys like a personal
development course without knowing
without reading the literature by
laughing it programs your mind and body
automatically and it creates a positive
mental attitude optimism like so many
bad things happen to me every day but I
say okay we'll see everything is going
to be okay though
so laughter builds a very good optimal
optimism hope and then if you have that
attitude but that will not come in a day
you have to be a regular laughter yogi
and I just want to share with you that
there are now there are no laughter
clubs in physical so now we have
laughter clubs on the zoom we have
laughter clubs on skype so if you go to
my website laughter yoga dot-org you can
find zoom
Skype online laughter clubs and almost
every half an hour there is a laughter
Club and you can join them I mean you
don't have to go to a laughter club if
you're busy you can just install zoom or
Skype on your mobile phone just laugh
anytime you got one more question how to
end a laughter yoga session you told us
how to start a session but how do we end
the session while finishing our laughter
session I think love is like a dynamic
energy boost your energy but we need
some kind of relaxation grounding
techniques so there are few things I
suggest for to end up the laughter
session one is humming what is called
bhramari pranayama when you close your
ears and just hum it out like relax
close your home and hum this is one
exercise you can do it ten times then
another exercise which is very good for
is unknown below point permit cross
breathing is very good for relaxing
right and third I suggest if you can
afford the best technique you can learn
is Yoga Nidra
Yoga Nidra is a audio available all over
the world on YouTube you can download
free just listen to standard some yoga
nidra audio and just lie down and relax
and you recharge your body and mind
buddy thank you doctor will take this
one last question that's coming in from
Sephora said from UAE laughter yoga
improves emotional intelligence yes or
no definitely see we all have negative
emotions stored in our subconscious mind
from the past
bad bad experiences we all have negative
experiences so there is laughter
exercises because it involves your
diaphragm it is works like a catharsis
what is what is called in psychology we
call psychological release
catharsis so it will relieve all the
negative baggage from the past and also
laughter will build and emotional
intelligence so that you are not
unnecessarily getting angry you are not
getting into argument with each other
and develop more resilience because
people get irritated at small small
things so by doing just by doing
laughter exercises we're happy to tell
you that one of the biggest tool people
want to learn is emotional intelligence
that can happen with laughter exercise
thank you thank you so much dr. Madan
Kataria any last message that you want
to give it to people who are watching us
right now one last message one last
message is that life is serious there's
a lot of seriousness in this world we
should start taking laughter seriously
now I see a lumbar I thank you so much
for joining us and given this giving us
the art and craft of laughing and I am
sure we can practice this at home and
only enhance our mindfulness but thank
you again by the guitar eeeh and yes one
more time thank you all the viewers
thank you ICS a long but I love you
thank you so much well do share your
feedback as suggestions by writing to us
on feedback using the hashtag wellness
360 at home and tag I see I see El
DeBarge
I repeat again please share your
feedback position on facebook using the
hashtag wellness 360 at home and tag
ICICI Lombard there was a first session
and first episode of wellness 360 at
home wait dr. Madan Kataria thank you so
much for joining us it was interesting
it was informative but more than that it
was all about laughter but keep loved
keep deliberating because life is all
about love and be beautiful
thank you so much again my name is with
the new party I namaste and we'll see
you soon for now keep laughing